Allan Ludwig Photograph Collection: New England Gravestones
Yale University Arts Library
- Isaac Morgin stone, 1696, Enfield, CT., redstone. One of the earliest extant stones in Enfield. Notice in particular the colons separatinf each word indicating an early lettering style already out of date in Boston after ca. 1675. 26.5 x 18 3/4. (Box 1)
- Issac Kibbe stone, 1766, Enfield, CT., redstone, 26 x 40. Fan topped stone with ornamental acanthus in border panels. (Box 1)
- Nathaniel Bissell stone, 1714, South Windsor, CT., redstone, 20.5 x 29. One of the first attempts at the thematic carving in the Connecticut Valley showing hte skull and bones theme so popular in Boston. (Box 1)
- Hannah Goodrich stone, 1721, Glastonbury, CT, redstone, 20 1/4 x 19.5. One of the earliest extant of the Tree of Life Theme in New England. (Box 1)
- Elezar Churchill stone, 1754, Plymouth, MA., slate, 22 x 26.5 Important example of Soule family carving in the ornamental style. See Dissertation section of Soule family. (Box 1)
- Sarah Hunt stone, 1799, Rumford, RI., slate. Signed by George Allen Jr. at base. (Box 1)
- English stone from Thorney, Cambridgeshire, England. Propably early 18th century showing Slain lamb as Allegory of the Passion of Christ. The theme of the lamn did not become popular in America until the 19th century when it was used in sentimental neo-classical imagery as morely-asleep. (Box 1)